# Muhammad Yaseen Taha

+92 3313 242615 yaseen20122001@gmail.com Karachi, Pakistan

#### ANDROID DEVELOPER

I am an experienced Android application developer with a strong foundation in application architecture, design, and development. I have a deep understanding of mobile application development and user interface design, with a track record of developing and launching applications for Android platforms. While my primary focus is on Android app development

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Techelix March 2024 - Present

# **Android Developer**

As an Android developer, I work on diverse projects, including a fitness app developed using Jetpack Compose. My responsibilities involve implementing new features like a rating system via API integration, ensuring app readiness for production, bug fixing, and incorporating new features into a student app. I handle multiple flavors of the student app for mass production.

#### Accomplishments:

- Contributing to the development of a fitness app, utilizing Jetpack Compose for UI design
- Exploring new features in Jetpack Compose, such as state management and composables
- Collaborating with the team to integrate rating system features using Jetpack Compose
- Participating in making the app production-ready with Jetpack Compose's modern UI toolkit
- Resolving bugs and errors in the Jetpack Compose-based fitness app
- Work on student app development, implementing new features and fixing bugs
- · Manage production of various flavor versions for different requirements

# Salsoft Technologies Sept 2022 - Present

# **Android Developer**

Created features for existing applications, including designing and implementing interfaces/layouts and integrating new features into existing code bases.

#### Accomplishments:

- Developing virtual private network application.
- · Adding features to existing applications.
- developed and launched mobile applications for Android TV and Amazon Fire TV platforms.
- Integrated DNS functions into apps, enhancing performance and user security.
- Implementation of payment methods in the app using Google Billing.
- Implemented clean code practices using MVVM and generics.
- Implemented in-app purchases using Google Billing.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams for on-time app delivery.
- Setup server to server notifications for auto-renewal subscriptions.
- · Experienced on the following modules in Android:-
- Google Billing, In-app purchases, Subscriptions, Building VPN connection using IKEV2 and IPSEC, Animations.

Si Global Solution May 2022 - Sept 2022

#### **Junior Android Developer**

Developed application upgrade of popular app with over 10M+ Downloads, adding features such as WhatsApp Delete-For-Everyone feature, upgrade FFmeg SDK.

#### Accomplishments:

- · Implemented features for various applications in Java, and Kotlin
- Develop Keyboard application from scratch adding feature like text to speech, implement api of book and music.
- Adding features to existing applications which over 10M+ Download

Linkitsoft Feb 2022 - May 2022

#### **Android Developer Internee**

Working as an Android developer intern, supported engineering team and contributed to the development of next-generation mobile applications.

#### Accomplishments:

- · Adding features to existing applications.
- Implementation of Translation Api MI-Kit in chatting application.
- Update Ui and fixed bugs

# **PROJECTS**

#### OysterVpn

Playstore: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oystervpn.app&hl=en&gl=US
Playstore (Android Tv): https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oystervpn.app&hl=en&gl=US
Amazon (Fire Tv): https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0CHVRK4MP
Description:

- Implementation of payment methods in the app using Google Billing.
- Implemented clean code practices using MVVM and generics.
- · Implemented in-app purchases using Google Billing.
- Developed Android Tv And Amazon FireTv App

#### **Status Saver For Whats**

**Playstore**: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.statussaverforwhatsapp **Description**:

- Implementation of function where if whatsapp contact delete the image in the chat so user can get deleted image in the app.
- Updated the FFmeg Api.

#### **Custom Keyboard**

#### **Description:**

Developed a native Android custom keyboard application with speech-to-text functionality and a built-in library of books and audio, utilizing Java and Android SDK.

- Implemented advanced speech recognition and natural language processing algorithms to enable accurate and efficient speech-to-text conversion.
- Designed a user-friendly interface that allows users to easily access and navigate the book library and audio content.
- Optimized the application's performance and memory usage to ensure smooth operation on a wide range of Android devices

#### **Chatting App**

#### **Description**:

- · Adding features to existing applications.
- Implementation of Translation Api MI-Kit in chatting application.
- Update Ui and fixed bugs

# Skills

- Android
- java/kotlin
- Android SDK, Android Jetpack (including libraries like LiveData, ViewModel, Room, etc.)
- UI/UX Design: XML layouts, Material Design guidelines, responsive UI development
- Networking and APIs: RESTful APIs, JSON/XML parsing, Retrofit, OkHttp
- Strong problem-solving and debugging skills
- Solid understanding of software development principles and design patterns
- Python
- Django Framework: Proficiency in Django, including knowledge of its core concepts, models, views, templates, forms, and URL routing.

# CERTIFICATION AND PERTIFICAPITION

#### **TECHTRON**

Techtrons was based on the concept of Fastest Finger First which means the students have to answer the questions of the online quiz quickly and correctly in order to earn maximum points. Techtrons had students from 15 countries participating in the competition.

# APTECH VISION - THE BIGGEST SOFTWARE EXHIBITION IN PAKISTAN

Aptech Vision is the embodiment of our vision for our students, which is to turn them into highly employable market-ready professionals.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Aptech Computer Education Center**

Advance Diploma in Software Engineering (Feb 2020 - Feb 2023)

#### Govt Degree collage, Lyari

FSC in pre-engineering (2017 - 2019)

# The English Access Microscholarship Program

The English Access Microscholarship Program (Access) provides a foundation of English language skills to bright, economically disadvantaged students, primarily between the ages of 13 to 20, in their countries.

#### ACHIEVEMENT

#### My web development Portfolio

My personal Web Development Portfolio. My Portfolio got mentioned by US-based famous YouTuber Dennis ivy, he mentioned my portfolio in the video best Portfolio.

Video Title: Portfolio Projects that Get you Hired Link: www.youtube.com/watch?v=SvtSza13sk8

Timestamps: 19:25